<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="acknowledge-v">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="accept or admit to the truth, existence, or knowledge of" type="">
        <commentary>
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She acknowledged that she might have forgotten his name.
            The Crown Prince was acknowledged as the true heir to the throne.
            We do not acknowledge your gods.
            Mr. Specter acknowledged the difficulties ahead.
            Respondents acknowledged the inexperience of their campaign staff.
            He acknowledged the noise but said that there was no excessive play.
            I acknowledge my mistakes and learn from them. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1,3,6</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>acknowledge.01</pb>
            <fn></fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="respond or show awareness of the receipt of an act" type="">
        <commentary>
            Note: An act can be a greeting, request, donation, message, question, gift,
            receipt, etc. Depending on the context, the response can be a show of appreciation. 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She acknowledged his compliment with a smile.
            We must acknowledge the kindness she showed towards us.
            Your generous contribution will be acknowledged with a gift card.
            Wiesel did not look at the young man or acknowledge his question in any way.
            The program committee acknowledged the submission of the authors of the paper.
            We will acknowledge the receipt of the package within a day or two of its arrival.
            The server acknowledges the message or sends an error message.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2,3,4</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>acknowledge.01</pb>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="mention as to give one's due recognition in speech or writing" type="">
        <commentary>
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It is important to acknowledge the work of others in one's own writing.
            He gave it to her and she acknowledged him in her speech.
            Helen Hunt acknowledged her by name in her acceptance speech when she won the Emmy.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1"></wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>acknowledge.01</pb>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="accept a document to be valid and legally binding" type="">
        <commentary>
            Further Note: to verify to a notary public or other officer (such as a County Clerk) 
            that the signer executed (wrote, signed) the document like a deed, lease, or power 
            of attorney, to make it certified as legal and suitable for recording.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The original lease was acknowledged before a notary public at the time it was executed.
            Under IC 45-1003, a trust deed must be acknowledged to be recordable.
            The power of attorney must be acknowledged by the principal before an authorized officer.
            Most recording statutes provide that the deed must be acknowledged before a notary public.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">5</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>acknowledge.01</pb>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
<sense group="1" n="5" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="duffield,hwangd" sample_score="-"/>

<ita count="122" ann_1_2_agreement="0.934426229508" />
</inventory>
