<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="call-n">
    <commentary>
        includes idioms on_call, at_call, within_call
        includes phrase port_of_call
    </commentary>
    <sense n="1" type="" name="a demand, request, summons" group="1">
        <commentary>
            CALL[+demand][+summons/+order/+request]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There was a general call to arms.
            John could not ignore the call to duty.
            Bob had to put ten grand into his short position when he got a margin call from the broker.
            After two raises in the hand of poker there was a call. (request to see the hands)
            There have been calls in Congress for his resignation.
            Our teacher does a roll call every morning. (A request for an answer)
            The cast had seven curtain calls.  (request to come take a bow)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">4,7,8,9</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="2" type="" name="an auditory signal that communicates something" group="1">
        <commentary>
            CALL[+signal][+audible][+communicative]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We heard small, plaintiff calls coming from the barn loft.
            John can imitate a number of bird calls very well.
            They heard the bugle call at dawn and dusk.
            The calls helped Bob figure out the sequence of steps during the square dance.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">3,5</wn>
            <wn version="MW online">9</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="3" type="" name="a brief visit, social or professional" group="1">
        <commentary>
            CALL[+visit][+brief]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The elderly sisters decided to make a call on their new neighbor.
            I know a vet who will make house calls.
            We paid a call to the Smiths when we were in town.
            The salesman is making a call on his most important customer.
            The doctor is out on a call.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">6,11</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="4" type="" name="telephone conversation" group="1">
        <commentary>
            CALL[+conversation][+telephone]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They keep in touch through long calls in the evening.
            Hold all my calls this afternoon.
            I'm trying to get a call through to Bolivia.
            I got a call at four saying the car was ready.
            Do you have call waiting on your phone?
            The hotel gave me a wake-up call at six this morning. (specialized conversation, alert)
            The weakening dollar could be a wake-up call for the Fed to act. (figurative)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="5" type="" name="an attraction, an inclination towards" group="1">
        <commentary>
            CALL[+state][+disposition][+attraction/+allure]
            Note: syntactically it looks like a summons (sense 1), but it describes an internal state of the subject, 
            so it is different than sense 1. 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The dogs felt the call of the wild on the family camping trip to the mountains.
            Her brother became a minister after he felt the call to God.
            These thrill seekers are susceptible to the call of danger.
            She followed the siren call of the sea, leaving home and job to sail the Pacific alone.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="6" type="" name="a judgement or decision" group="1">
        <commentary>
            CALL[+act][+mental][+judgement]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Fans believe the umpire made a bad call in the seventh inning.
            The president has a tough call to make on this one.
            John made the call of heads, but the coin turned up tails.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="7" type="" name="computer program instruction" group="1">
        <commentary>
            CALL[+instruction][+computer]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Does this program use calls by value or calls by reference?
            After the call to the subroutine, the program returns control to the main process.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">10</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="8" type="" name="an option to buy a stock or future at a certain price by a date" group="1">
        <commentary>
            CALL[+option][+stock][+purchase]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            What are the September calls on Microsoft trading for today?
            Mary let her call options on some energy stocks expire. 
            That broker is selling both puts and calls on a bundle of technology stocks.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">13</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="9" type="" name="available, ready to assist" group="1">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: on_call
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Three surgeons are on call tonight in the emergency ward.
            Security guards are on call twenty-four hours a day there.
            Our staff is on call to serve all your needs throughout your stay here.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">on_call</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="10" type="" name="at one's command or summons" group="1">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: at_call
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The famous chef has a dozen well-trained assistants at his call.
            The emperor had fifty thousand men at his call.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">at_call</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="11" type="" name="within hearing or summons" group="1">
        <commentary>
            Idiom within_call
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Dogs may be off leash but within call of their owner's voice commands.
            Are we within call of that island yet?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">within_call</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="12" type="" name="ports visited by a ship, other than home port" group="1">
        <commentary>
            phrase: port_of_call
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Our cruise included six ports of call in the Caribbean.
            John thought Antalya, Turkey was the most interesting port of  call on their trip.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">port_of_call</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense group="1" n="13" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1"></wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
            <fn></fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>

<ita count="130" ann_1_2_agreement="0.9" />
</inventory>
