<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="deal-v">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="handle or manage, exert some control over" type="">
        <commentary>
            Syntax Is:
            NP1[agent] DEAL PP
            NOTE: usually: WITH NP[issue, problem, conditions]
            Includes: DEAL WITH
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            How are we going to deal with this problem?
            She deals with problems as simple as migraines or as complex families falling apart.
            He works hard to gain an understanding of the information that he deals with every day.
            Both teams dealt with poor weather conditions.
            I think that I have dealt with not having a drink for eight months.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2,4,7,10</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>deal.01</pb>
            <vn>cope-83</vn><fn>NP</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="interact with others and within society" type="">
        <commentary>
            Syntax Is:
            NP1[agent] DEAL PP
            Note: usually: WITH  NP[human])
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This job requires good problem solving ability, verbal and written communication skills, and the ability to deal with others.
            Too many people lead unhappy lives due to an inability to deal with others.
            The spanked children then imitate parental anger when they deal with other children.
            The depression left me with not wanting to deal with my family or friends.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">8</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>deal.01</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="consider, address, look at, focus on a particular topic" type="">
        <commentary>
            Syntax Is:
            NP1[topic] DEAL PP
            Note: usually: WITH  NP[content, meaning]
            Note: This usually refers to content or meaning of a written or spoken material.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The report dealt with the national efforts to implement the Convention against Torture.
            Here we deal with the following case.
            A number of global reports produced by ILO have dealt with poverty.
            This book deals with alcohol and drug abuse.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1,3</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>deal.01</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="distribute or portion out" type="">
        <commentary>
            Includes: DEAL OUT
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The cook came with the dishes and dealt out the rations.
            This is the water which all the estates receive in turn, dealt out to them on regular days.
            Bad provisions, bad water, and scanted rations were dealt to the prisoners.
            Unfortunately fate has dealt a cruel blow and we have little choice but to move on.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">5,11</wn>
            <wn lemma="deal_out" version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="distribute to players in a game" type="">
        <commentary>
            Note: may be used metaphorically (see examples)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Just because Fate doesn't deal you the right cards, it doesn't mean you should give up.
            A total of four cards are initially dealt by the dealer or a player in the game. 
            He dealt me the King of Spades.
            The game begins with each player being dealt a "loyalty" card.
            You play the hand you're dealt.
            The number of bones dealt at start of the game varies in different parts of the world.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">9,12</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>deal.02</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="sell" type="">
        <commentary>
            Syntax Is:
            NP1[agent] DEAL PP
            Note:usually: WITH NP[object for sale, especially illegal materials])
            Includes: DEAL WITH
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            People have sent us a clear message they do not want people who deal drugs to live among them.
            The state stripped him of both his business license and his license to deal cars.
            People who deal in marijuana are likely to deal in other illicit drugs.
            Later he dealt arms in Latin America.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">6,13</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>deal.01</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
<sense group="1" n="7" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="duffielc" sample_score="-"/>

<ita count="216" ann_1_2_agreement="0.708333333333" />
</inventory>
