<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="fact-n">
    <commentary>
        12Jun08 - merged senses 1 and 3, revised features, examples, defs. ahouston
        Includes idioms in_fact, facts_of_life
    </commentary>
    
    <sense n="1" type="" name="empirical data, information, relevant to a context" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FACT[+information][+data][+evidence][+empirical]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The architect gave us the facts and figures on the plans for the new library.
            The tabloids contain many alleged facts about the romantic lives of movie stars.
            The lawyers have been reviewing the facts of the case for weeks now.
            The facts don't support John's belief in a perpetual motion machine.
            This account of the general's life is not based on fact, but only conjecture and hearsay.
            The fact that the earth goes around the sun was controversial in earlier times.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1,2,4</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="2" type="" name="a state of reality versus fantasy or fiction" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FACT[+state][+circumstance][+reality][-fictional]
            Note: refers to a whole situation or state that is real, not a collection of supporting information (Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Space exploration is now a fact.
            High infant mortality was a fact of life in medieval times.
            He lacks the experience for the job and that's a fact. 
            The fact that there will be layoffs next month has caused a lot of anxiety at work. (future state of affairs assumed to be certain to come about)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">3</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="3" type="" name="DO NOT CHOOSE" group="1">
        <commentary>
            
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">Do Not Choose</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="4" type="" name="the act of a crime" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FACT[+event][+crime]
            Note: usage in police and legal investigations
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The prosecutor argued that the murderer had dragged the body into the kitchen after the fact.
            She was considered an accessory after the fact.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">1b</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="5" type="" name="in truth" group="1">
        <commentary>
            Idiom in_fact (a discourse parenthetical)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            In fact, John doesn't have any real friends.
            The dissidents were, in fact, trying to overthrow their government.
            Well, in fact, I was thinking exactly the same thing!
            In point of fact, Mary wasn't his real aunt but just a close friend of the family.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">idiom</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="6" type="" name="sexual reproduction" group="1">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: sexual reproduction
            Note: idiom is always in the plural
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary is trying to figure out when to tell her children the facts of life.
            They are so sheltered that no one ever teaches them the facts of life.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
<sense group="1" n="7" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>

<ita count="372" ann_1_2_agreement="0.913978494624" />
</inventory>
