<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="flight-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense n="1" type="" name="the general process of traveling through the air" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FLIGHT[+activity][+process][+flying]
            Note: does not imply travel by airplane (see Sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Have you ever seen an eagle in flight?
            Space flight did not become a reality until the 20th century.
            In Greek mythology, Icarus' flight takes him too close to the sun and his wings melt.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="2" type="" name="travel by airplane" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FLIGHT[+activity][+travel][+airplane]
            Note: implies the actual ongoing process of traveling in an airplane.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            How was your flight from Munich?
            During the flight we watched a movie.
            I didn't like my frequent red-eye flights between the coasts last year.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="3" type="" name="the trajectory of a flying object" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FLIGHT[+form][+trajectory]
            Note: implies a single gravitationally-influenced arc, not a sustained process using wing lift.
            Note: focus is on the form of the traversed path, not the activity of being airborne
            Note: rockets may escape the gravitational field, but they are not airborne because of wing lift, but pure propulsion.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The arrow's flight was a parabolic arc from the bow to the target.
            The white plume of exhaust defined the rocket's flight into the heavens.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">7</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="4" type="" name="a sequence or set of similar objects, usually steps, stairs" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FLIGHT[+sequence][+object][+similar][+stair/+glass/+lock/+hurdle]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We walked up three flights of stairs.
            The waiter in the wine bar brought us a flight of Oregon Pinot Noirs to sample. (set of small glasses for tasting)
            The flight of locks through the canal took several hours to navigate.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">3</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="5" type="" name="a display of great imagination or fancy" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FLIGHT[+activity][+display][+imaginative][+highly]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The children engage in wonderful flights of fancy as they played in the old barn. 
            The teacher encourages her students to allow their imaginations to take flight.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">6</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="6" type="" name="groups of airborne entities, e.g., planes, birds" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FLIGHT[+group][+airborne][+aircraft/+bird]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Air traffic control sequenced the flights into a figure eight over the airport. 
            The flight suddenly disappeared from the radar screen.
            We watched flights of Canada geese soar overhead in formation.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1,8</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="7" type="" name="a scheduled trip by air" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FLIGHT[+plan][+schedule][+itinerary]
            Note: focus is on the published schedule of a flight, not the activity of being airborne
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Can you find any non-stop morning flights between Dallas and Miami?
            I am standing by for the next flight to Paris. (focus is on the specific flight number)
            Flights out of Providence are usually cheaper than the ones out of Boston.
            The airlines publish their flight schedules about once a month.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">9</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="8" type="" name="the act of escaping, fleeing" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FLIGHT[+action][+escape]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They read about the Jewish people's flight from Egypt.
            The book describes her flight from an abusive relationship.
            Miami airport was crowded with pale New Englanders in their flight from the cold winter. (figurative)
            We felt the rapid flight of summer days. (metaphoric extension)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">4</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="9" type="" name="an air force military unit, smaller than a squadron" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FLIGHT[+group][+unit][+military][+air_force]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John and Bob flew in the same flight in the Air Force.
            Their flight lost two pilots in a training mission.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">5</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="10" type="" name="the tail of a dart" group="1">
        <commentary>
            FLIGHT[+artifact][+component][+dart][+tail]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John held the dart by its flight and aimed at the dart board.
            The flights of the darts were painted red and green.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">6</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
<sense group="1" n="11" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>

<ita count="80" ann_1_2_agreement="1.0" />
</inventory>
