<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="line-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    <sense n="1" type="" name="a queue or sequence of things or events" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+arrangement][+queue]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We stood in line two hours to get tickets.
            The bread line stretched all the way around the block.
            It was a strange line of events that led to the start of World War I. 
            They had to shut down two assembly lines last night at the plant.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1,3,10,29</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="2" type="" name="an elongated form with little (or no) breadth" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+form][+elongation]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Draw two lines across and two lines down to make a tic-tac-toe grid.
            Euclid conceived of lines as having infinite extension in one dimension.
            These spectral lines indicate the presence of sodium among the elements of that star.
            The line around the middle of the earth is called the equator.
            Her face had lines around the eyes from years in the sun.
            John laid out six lines of cocaine on the mirror.
            We could see several lines of jet trail in the sky.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2,4,6,11,12</wn>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">3c,3g</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="3" type="" name="unit of a larger whole text, picture or melody" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+unit][+text/+music/+picture]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Each couplet of the poem consists of two lines.
            Your display monitor is composed of lines of pixels.
            This paper charged a lot per line to run our ad. 
            John added a couple of his own lines to the symphonic score.
            She only drops me a line now and again. (metaphoric)
            Jane forgot her opening lines of the play.	
            There's a great line in that movie.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">5,24,26,27</wn>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">2d,2e</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="4" type="" name="argumentation, often spoken" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+activity][+argumentation]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            You won't believe the line that guy tried on me last night in the bar.
            The tobacco industry's lawyers have used that same line for years.
            Your line of reasoning seems flawed somewhere.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">8</wn>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">4c</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="5" type="" name="a conduit that conveys  or transports something" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+conduit][+physical/+social]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The storm brought down a lot of power lines.
            John has three phone lines going into his house.
            The Alaskan pipe line was a controversial project.
            They bombed all the rail lines going into the city.
            These lines etched on the circuit board convey electrons.
            The enemy destroyed our supply lines so no food got to the front.
            She's searching for any line of communication with her son.
            Our firm has excellent lines of communication with our suppliers and clients.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">9,13,14,15,21</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="6" type="" name="a boundary or demarcation" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+relation][+demarcation]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The enemy breached our front line in two places.
            The referee said the player's foot was over the line when he still had the ball.
            They carried the ball to the twenty-yard line.
            You were way out of line last night. (metaphoric)
            She's good at keeping those headstrong children in line.
            Sometimes there is a fine line between genius and insanity.
            Critics believe the President has stepped over the line of legality.
            Georgia's offensive line has reacted quickly to the ball.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">7,18,20,28</wn>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">6k</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="7" type="" name="relation of inheritance or pedigree" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+relation][+inheritance]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The evolutionary line from flatworm to human is long and arduous.
            He comes from a long line of liars.
            One line of my family tree can be traced back to Scotland.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">17</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="8" type="" name="a slender rope, cord or thread" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+cordage]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I bought some new rope to replace lines on my sailboat.
            Hang the sheets on the line to dry in the sun.
            John just caught something on his line!
            Use a mason's line to set these bricks properly.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">18</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="9" type="" name="vocation or career" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+activity][+vocation]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            That's a dangerous line of work he's in.
            I was in that line of business years ago. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">19</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="10" type="" name="style or brand of merchandise" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+merchandise][+style]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They make an expensive line of stereo speaker.
            Our company is starting a new line of swim wear this spring
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">22</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="11" type="" name="transportation enterprise or company" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+enterprise][+transportation]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            How many routes does the Peter Pan bus line provide?
            We booked our trip on an Italian cruise line.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">23</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="12" type="" name="an allowed limit, usually of credit" group="1">
        <commentary>
            LINE[+quantity][+limit]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We've set up a line of credit for our small company.
            Sally went over the line on her credit card last month.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">25</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
<sense group="1" n="13" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>

<ita count="201" ann_1_2_agreement="1.0" />
</inventory>


