<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="plan-n">
    <commentary>
        examples and definitions revised, comments added. ahouston
        21aug07 - modified features, added to commentary ahouston
        23Apr08 - revised features and commentary, Sense 2., added sense 4 ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense n="1" type="" name="an objective or goal" group="1">
        <commentary>
            PLAN[+state][+mental][+intention][+goal]
            Note: refers to an intention or goal, without implying a specific strategy or policy to achieve it.
            Note: refers to intentions of an agent/actor 'X's plans'  'John's plan'
            Note: 'X has plans'  means the same as 'X's plans' where X is agent/actor
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Bill's father has plans to retire in another year.  (he intends to do so)
            We have no plans for the weekend.
            Her plan to become a vegetarian dissolved at the sight of the juicy steak.
            The playboy's plans did not include marrying any of the women he was dating.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="2" type="" name="a strategy, proposed sequence of steps to attain a goal" group="1">
        <commentary>
            PLAN[+procedure][+strategy][+proposal][+for_attainment][+of_goal]
            Note: refers to a set of specified steps and actions to accomplish a goal, not just the intention 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They have come up with a peace plan that looks promising.
            The candidate hired Phil to work out the master plan for his presidential campaign.
            The sales team has drawn up a battle plan for going after those new accounts. (figurative)
            Her mother's micro-managing of the wedding plans was driving everyone crazy.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="3" type="Architectural" name="a schematic, e.g., blueprint" group="1">
        <commentary>
            PLAN[+entity][+concrete][+artifact][+drawing][+schematic]
            a schematic, a diagram
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The plans for City Hall were on file.
            Have you seen the floor plan of our new house?
            This plan appears not to be drawn to scale.
            Several architectural plans are currently being reviewed for the proposed new library.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">3</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="4" type="" name="a contract, often involving regular monetary contributions to some end" group="1">
        <commentary>
            PLAN[+artifact][+contract][+legal][+payment][+for_benefit]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Our company has a 401k plan but no pension plan.
            The bank is restructuring their payment plan in order to avoid foreclosure.
            They paid for the American plan at that resort because it includes a big breakfast.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1a</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
<sense group="1" n="5" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>

<ita count="258" ann_1_2_agreement="1.0" />
</inventory>
