<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="require-v">    
    <commentary>
        No VPCs to add
    </commentary>
    <sense n="1" type="" name="need, call for, be suitable for" group="1">  
        <commentary>
            Syntax Is: NP1[recipient] REQUIRE NP2[topic] (COMP)
            NOTE: usually can be paraphrased with "need":
            OK:  The company requires/needs a photo ID from every potential seller.
            NOT OK: They must comply within the time that the law requires/*needs.
            NOTE: NP1 is not an authority placing a demand, but a recipient of something
            NOTE: The first example below can be transformed to 'It requires hand dexterity to be a surgeon'.
        </commentary>
        <examples> 
            Being a surgeon requires excellent hand dexterity.
            These accounts require some further going over.
            The refugees will require food and shelter for at least a month.
            Six years ago when German Mutual's growth required a new computer system.
            My broken arm is requiring more time to heal than I expected.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1,4</wn>   
            <wn lemma="" version="2.1"></wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>require.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense n="2" type="" name="command or compel someone " group="1">  
        <commentary>
            Syntax Includes:
            NP1 REQUIRE NP2[patient] COMP[nonfinite]
            NP1 REQUIRE THAT SCOMP[subjunctive]
            NOTE: Subject (usually an agent, but can be a situation) is placing a demand,
            not receiving something from someone.
            NOTE: Cannot do extrapositions with it  **It requires our staff to wear tuxedos'
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The security guard required us to sign in at the front desk.
            We require our serving staff to wear tuxedos.
            The statute required that the defendant would be sentenced to death.
            John's children are required to clean their rooms once a week.
            The SEC requires that companies file these forms annually.
            The Department argued that the law requires accessible pedestrian routes.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2,3</wn>
            <wn lemma="" version="2.1"></wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>require.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
<sense group="1" n="3" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston,vieweg,duffielc" sample_score="-"/>
     

<ita count="278" ann_1_2_agreement="0.791366906475" />
</inventory>
