<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="sense-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense n="1" type="" name="general awareness of something" group="1">
        <commentary>
            SENSE[+state][+mental][+awareness][+general]
            Note: implies a specific focus of awareness, not a general ability (see Sense 5)
            Note: focus is on cognition rather than specific physical perceptions (Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The children felt no sense of danger as they proceeded into the mine shaft.
            This bed will provide your pet with a sense of security.
            They resumed their task with a renewed sense of purpose.
            I had a sense that she wanted us to leave her alone.
            The murderer showed no sense of shame.
            Bob has the sense that business is not going well for his brother's firm.
            He supported his aging parents out of a sense of duty.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="2" type="" name="the meaning of a word or an expression" group="1">
        <commentary>
            SENSE[+meaning][+linguistic]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It is not clear from this passage which sense of 'character' is meant.
            Some of the subtle senses in this poem cannot be translated.
            How many different senses can you list for the word 'run'?
            We could not make sense of this situation. (interpret its meaning)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="3" type="" name="the faculties of perception, e.g., seeing, smelling" group="1">
        <commentary>
            SENSE[+quality][+faculty][+perception][+sight/+hearing/+touch/+taste/+smell]
            Note: focus is on inherent physical faculties of perception of the outside world.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Dogs have an extremely keen sense of smell.
            The cool air and beauty of the mountain awakened all our senses.
            Pete's grandfather has lost his sense of hearing.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">3</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="4" type="" name="good judgement, sound reasoning" group="1">
        <commentary>
            SENSE[+quality][+faculty][+judgement][+good]
            Note: implies an ability in general to reason clearly, think rationally
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She showed good sense in handling that crisis at work.
            Those kids skateboarding through traffic have no sense at all!
            Has she lost her senses to go out with a guy like that?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">4</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="5" type="" name="individual aptitude or ability" group="1">
        <commentary>
            SENSE[+aptitude][+individual]
            Note: implies ability in a given individual, not species-wide ability (see Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A good comedian needs a sense of timing.
            That dancer has a great sense of rhythm. 
            Joan has a poor sense of direction.
            Mary has a good sense of humor.
            The loud fraternity boys offended the girl's sense of decorum. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">5</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="6" type="" name="rationale or justification for an action" group="1">
        <commentary>
            SENSE[+relation][+rationale][+action]
            Note: the reasons that support making a decision or acting in some way
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It makes no sense to check our bags if we are planning to standby for an earlier flight.
            What's the sense of sitting around moping?
            That decision makes a lot of sense, given their situation.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">3b</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="7" type="" name="one of two opposites, as of direction of motion" group="1">
        <commentary>
            SENSE[+relation][+opposite][+direction]
            Note: a narrow usage referring to the opposite behaviors of otherwise identical entities. 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The sense of one particle emitted from the collision is the opposite direction of the other.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">7</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
<sense group="1" n="8" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>

<ita count="132" ann_1_2_agreement="0.977272727273" />
</inventory>
