<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="star-n">
    <commentary>
        Includes idiom: see_stars
    </commentary>
    
    <sense n="1" type="" name="self-illuminating gaseous celestial bodies" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STAR[+body][+celestial][+self_illuminating]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The nearest star to our solar system is about four light years away.
            A neutron star no longer emits light. (But it once did, so it qualifies)
            Betelgeuse is a star that can be seen with the naked eye.
            Imagery from the telescope revealed a star nursery within the nebula.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1,3</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="2" type="" name="a hotshot or ace, a gifted person or animal" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STAR[+individual][+skilled][+exceptionally]
            Note: focus is on ability, aptitude, not fame or prominence (see Sense 4)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John was a track star in high school.
            The young professor from Argentina is considered a rising star in the field of economics. (figurative)
            We watched the all star game on television. (top sports players)
            She proved to be the star of the debating club.
            That three-year-old filly is one of this year's stars on the racing circuit.
            One of the Red Sox's star pitchers received an injury last night when a ball struck his shin.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="3" type="" name="a geometric plane figure, typically with five points" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STAR[+figure][+plane][+point][+five]
            Note: A star may have more points, but not less than five.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary hung a star on top of the Christmas tree.
            The child drew a six-pointed star on the page.
            You can cut the cookie dough into stars or circles, or other shapes.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">4</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="4" type="" name="a famous, principal participant,  e.g., entertainers, headliners" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STAR[+entertainer][+famous]
            [+role][+performer][+principal]
            Note: focus is on fame, notoriety and prominence, rather than ability or aptitude. (see Sense 2)
            Note: often refers to entertainers, but can include politicians, witnesses and others who play a central role in something.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The woman sitting at the next table is a famous opera star.
            Many film stars attended the opening last night.
            The director is looking for a star to play the leading man.
            Penguins are the stars in that documentary.
            John is singing backup vocals for that famous rock star.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">5,6</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="5" type="" name="notation, an asterisk" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STAR[+notation][+asterisk]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            An asterisk is also called the star character.
            Enter the numbers and then hit the star key.
            I put a star next to the items on the task list that I must get finished today.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">7</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="6" type="" name="a network topology, a network configuration" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STAR[+topology][+form]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A star network topology has a central hub unlike a ring network.
            The company has linked several star networks together to form a hybrid.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">8</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="7" type="" name="a white marking on the nose of an animal, e.g., horse" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STAR[+marking][+nose][+animal]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary's chestnut stallion has a white star on his forehead.
            The kitten was all black except for a white star on his face.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">2c</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="8" type="" name="destiny, fate, horoscope" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STAR[+state][+destiny][+horoscope]
            Note: 'stars' includes planets in this sense, harkening back to the times when the planets were noticed to be 'wandering stars', distinct from the fixed stars. 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            You should thank your lucky stars!
            She believes her fate is written in the stars.
            The stars say you will meet a handsome stranger today.
            His star has faded of late. (figurative sense, his power and fate are not going well)
            He was born under an unlucky star.
            Observers have been watching China's rising star. (figurative, good fortune)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">2</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="9" type="" name="a judgement of excellence" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STAR[+event][+judgement][+excellence]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Pierre's restaurant received its third Michelin star this year.
            The teacher put a gold star on Johnny's spelling test, and a silver one on Tommy's.
            They stayed at a four-star hotel on Barbados.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">2a</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="10" type="" name="experience visual effects from hitting the head" group="1">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: see_stars
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Pete saw stars when the lid of the piano fell down on his head.
            I'd better sit down for a moment because I'm still seeing stars.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">see_stars</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
<sense group="1" n="11" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>

<ita count="74" ann_1_2_agreement="0.891891891892" />
</inventory>
