<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="station-n">
    <commentary>
        28aug06 updated to wordnet 2.1 ahouston
        28aug06 added features, and more examples, modified definitions. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense n="1" type="" name="a facility that provides services" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STATION[+entity][+building][+facility][+service][+transportation/+safety/+farming/+research]
            a facility equipped with special equipment and personnel for a
            particular purpose
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He started looking for a gas station.
            The train pulled out of the station right on time.
            She grew up on a sheep station in western Australia. (Australian term for 'farm', includes buildings)
            John spent six months at a research station in Antarctica. 
            He was taken downtown to the police station for questioning.
            There was a large turnout at the polling stations on Tuesday's election.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="2" type="" name="one's assigned social rank or status" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STATION[+state][+social][+status][+assigned]
            proper or designated social status
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The older members of the club felt the newcomer had overstepped his station in speaking out.
            The responsibilities of a man in his station are numerous.
            She married above her station.
            The people in this small village seem happy with their station in life.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="3" type="" name="an assigned post of duty, a location where duties are done" group="1">
        <commentary>
            STATION[+location][+post][+duty][+assigned][+military/+medical/+manufacturing/+hospitality]
            Note: refers to a spot where specific duties are carried out.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The commander of the warship ordered all hands to their battle stations.
            Who is on-duty after midnight at the nurses' station?
            The squadron's station will be in southern Kuwait.
            The inspectors walked across the factory floor, stopping at each worker's station.
            The head butler ordered all his staff to their stations as the first guest arrived at the manor.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">3 4</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
<sense group="1" n="4" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>

<ita count="132" ann_1_2_agreement="0.954545454545" />
</inventory>
