<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="team-n">
    <commentary>
        Added a fourth group, revised groups 1 and 2, revised examples, commentary, and definitions. ahouston.
    </commentary>
    <sense n="1" type="" name="cooperative social unit, often competitive" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TEAM[+group][+human][+cooperative]
            A cooperative unit 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary is the captain of the debating team.
            The foreman is putting two teams of men on this section of roadbed.
            The losing team will not get to participate in the championship games.
            The pro baseball teams are in spring training now.
            How is Team USA doing in the downhill competition?
            We set up a tag team to take care of John's convalescing mother.
            Marketing has set up three teams to create concepts for the new product launch.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense n="2" type="" name="harnessed draft animals pulling a vehicle or implement" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TEAM[+group][+animal][+draft][+harnessed]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There were 20-mule teams hauling borax across Death Valley during the nineteenth century.
            Jack hitched his team of oxen up to the covered wagon.
            The Queen's carriage had a matched team of prancing chestnut thoroughbreds.
            During the Iditarod, John put straw down for his team of huskies to sleep on at night.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2-</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense n="3" type="Slang" name="homosexual" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TEAM[+group][+human][+orientation][+sexual]
            Slang for a sexual preference (usually homosexual) 
            Note: metaphoric extension of Sense 1
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Those girls holding hands over there are clearly playing for the other team.
            George realized he had switched teams when he found himself competing
            with Suzy for Bob's attention.  
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="??">?-</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense n="4" type="Slang" name="brood or group of young animals" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TEAM[+animal][+brood][+young]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We had to watch our step among the squealing team of piglets running through our legs.
            A team of ducklings waddled up the bank of the lake towards the children offering bread.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">3-</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
<sense group="1" n="5" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>

<ita count="245" ann_1_2_agreement="0.967346938776" />
</inventory>
