<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="throw-v">    
    <commentary>
        Contains duplicate WN mappings.
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="Propel or hurl something/someone with
   force; toss or put forward an idea or gesture." type="">  
        <commentary>
            Syntax includes: NP1[agent] THROW NP2[patient] (PP{P NP})
            NP1[agent] THROW NP2[patient] (ADVP)
            Includes: THROW BACK, THROW IN, THROW TOGETHER
            NOTE: Compare to sense 9. In sense 1, a patient is being
            thrown. Sense 1 does not involve giving up or quitting. 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The delinquents threw a brick through the school window.
            My friend threw the ball back over the fence.
            He threw a punch at his attacker.
            The horse reared and threw the rider into the bushes.
            He threw sixes on both die.
            She threw herself enthusiastically into the project.
            He finally got the message after she almost threw herself at him.
            The earthquake threw them onto the floor.
            Others threw insults and abusive words my way.
            She instantly spun around and threw me a scowl.
            The pirates then grasped him and threw him overboard.
            The beauty queen threw kisses at the crowd. 
            She hangs out while the boys fight and throw money around.
            He abruptly stopped and threw a glance at me, but he didn't react.
            She threw me a look of encouragement.
            He threw in a couple of wisecracks during her speech.
            I'm just throwing my ideas out there. Let me know what you think.
            Here are some ideas and examples to throw out.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1,2,4,5,8,10,13,14</wn>   
            <wn lemma="throw_overboard" version="2.1">1,2</wn>
            <wn lemma="throw_back" version="2.1">1</wn>
            <wn lemma="throw_in" version="2.1">3</wn>
            <wn lemma="throw_out" version="2.1">5</wn>
            <wn lemma="throw_together" version="2.1">1,2</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>throw.01</pb>
            <vn>throw-17.1-1-1</vn><fn>Body_movement</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="Discard, dispose, expel, or get rid of." type="">
        <commentary>
            Includes: THROW AWAY, THROW OFF
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Throw your worries into the wind!
            I have always wished I could cut things out and throw the old magazines away.
            So throw away your old habits and regain your confidence.
            He can't seem to throw off the bad first impression he made on Sally.
            Let's try to throw off this guy who's been following us across town.
            So, before you throw out the trash, see what you can recycle.
            They mistook him for a kid in a costume and threw him out of the bar.
            We need to calm down before we are thrown out of the room.
            That proposal was thrown out of the committee last year.
            The case was thrown out yesterday after the judges became impatient with delays.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">3</wn>
            <wn lemma="throw_away" version="2.1">1,2</wn>
            <wn lemma="throw_off" version="2.1">1,2</wn>
            <wn lemma="throw_out" version="2.1">1,2,3,4,6</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="Manipulate or move something in order to operate." type="">
        <commentary>
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John threw the car into reverse and squealed the tires.
            They threw the switch just as the train was approaching.
            He reversed the engine and threw the lever back.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">6,8</wn>
            <wn lemma="" version="2.1"></wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
            <vn>throw-17.1-1-1</vn><fn>NM</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="Cast, emit, or radiate." type="">
        <commentary>
            Includes: THROW LIGHT
            Note: (metaphorical usage meaning 'to cast understanding')
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Is the fireplace throwing any heat yet?
            We threw the tape of vacation highlights up on the screen for the audience.
            We can put up a reflector to throw light into the dark places
            This workshop will throw light into the dark corners of your mind.
            The searchlights are throwing out powerful beams.
            My wizard doesn't throw spells around left and right.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">7</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="Confuse or bewilder" type="">
        <commentary>
            Include: THROW OFF, THROW OFF KILTER, THROW OUT OF KILTER
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary was really thrown by his unexpected apology.
            The game contestants were thrown by that last clue.
            Don't be thrown off by these equations; the underlying concept is simple.
            Maybe your remarks threw him off kilter.
            When you stop paying attention to her mistakes, you will throw her out of kilter.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">9,15</wn>
            <wn lemma="throw_out_of_kilter" version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
            <vn>amuse-31.1</vn><fn>NM</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="Hold an event" type="">  
        <commentary>
            Includes: THROW A FIT
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Our department is throwing Jim a farewell party.
            Mary threw an informal get-together at her place last night.
            She'll throw a fit when she sees what you've done with her toys.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">11</wn>   
            <wn lemma="throw_a_fit" version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>throw.02</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="Form or shape, as pottery" type="">
        <commentary>
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We watched the potter throw a large vase on his wheel.
            John is going down to the ceramics studio to throw a few pots this afternoon.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">12</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="Lose, as a game, intentionally" type="">
        <commentary>
            Note: NOT THROW IN, THROW IN THE TOWEL; compare to Sense 10.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They were suspected of throwing the game last Sunday.
            Deep Blue threw the match!
            Will the current chair throw the elections to the new candidate?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn lemma="" version="2.1"></wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="Give up, quit" type="">
        <commentary>
            Includes: THROW IN, THROW IN THE TOWEL
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Bob is ready to throw it in on this endless legal battle.
            They have decided to throw in the towel about fighting the rezoning commission.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn lemma="throw_in" version="2.1">2</wn>
            <wn lemma="throw_in_the_towel" version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="THROW UP: vomit" type="">
        <commentary>
            Is: THROW UP
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Obviously the shellfish we just ate disagreed with me. I just threw up.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn lemma="throw_up" version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="11" name="THROW IN: add as an extra or gratuity" type="">
        <commentary>
            Is: THROW IN
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The landlord threw in a free month of rent and let them move in two weeks early.
            When I bought my new glasses, they threw in a free pair of sunglasses.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn lemma="throw_in" version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
            <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
<sense group="1" n="12" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston,hwangd,corvey,greenlm" sample_score="-"/>
     

<ita count="91" ann_1_2_agreement="0.791208791209" />
</inventory>
