<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="traffic-n">
    <commentary>
        Definition, examples and commentary revised by ahouston
        Idiom added.
    </commentary>
    <sense n="1" type="" name="a moving aggregate of bodies, as cars and pedestrians" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TRAFFIC[+aggregate][+moving][+bodies]
            the aggregation of things (pedestrians and vehicles) coming and going
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I have to leave the house at six in the morning to beat the traffic.
            The TSA has to process heavy traffic through JFK airport every day of the week.
            We had to steer clear of some commercial boat traffic as we sailed out of Boston Harbor.
            The traffic came to a standstill on I-93 after a four-car accident.
            They don't get much traffic through their store because of its out-of-the-way location.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense n="2" type="" name="information that travels through communication devices" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TRAFFIC[+aggregate][+moving][+information]
            the amount of activity over a communication system during a period of time 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Traffic on the internet is lightest during the night.
            This new switching system can accommodate twice the phone traffic that was handled by the old one.
            The NSA intercepted some interesting traffic through a cell tower that connects to overseas.
            My calling plan doesn't count minutes at night or on weekends when traffic is lowest.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">3</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense n="3" type="" name="trading of goods and services, often illicit trade" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TRAFFIC[+activity][+exchange][+trade]
            buying and selling; especially illicit trade
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The no-gum rule at school only enticed the kids and resulted in an increase in gum traffic.
            There is a light traffic of villagers' blankets and ceramics at the weekly farmer's market.
            The drug traffic did not appear to decrease even after the big bust by the feds last week.
            The slave traffic was prolific in America between the 16th and 19th centuries.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense n="4" type="" name="social or verbal interchange, discourse" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TRAFFIC[+exchange][+social][+discourse]
            social or verbal interchange (often followed by 'with')
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He was court-martialed for having traffic with the enemy.
            There was a lively traffic in ideas about search technology at the last conference.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">4</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense n="5" type="" name="what existing conditions will allow" group="1">
        <commentary>
            the traffic will bear/allow - Idiom
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Just charge what you think the traffic will bear.
            "everything that traffic will allow" (from the song 'No business like show business')
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">idiom</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
<sense group="1" n="6" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett" sample_score=""/>

<ita count="44" ann_1_2_agreement="0.977272727273" />
</inventory>
