<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="tube-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense n="1" type="" name="conduit that transports gases, liquids or objects" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TUBE[+artifact][+cylindrical][+hollow][+conduit][+gas/+liquid/+object]
            Note: implies it has a function to pass something through it (not true of Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A catheter is a glass tube inserted in the body to drain liquid.
            Blue and green liquids flowed through a series of glass tubes in the laboratory.
            They inserted a feeding tube down the patient's throat.
            The contraption has ping pong balls rolling down tubes onto springboards.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="2" type="" name="a vacuumized electronic device" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TUBE[+artifact][+cylindrical][+hollow][+electronic][+vacuum]
            Note: always implies the movement of electrons through a device
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Before transistors, many electronic devices used vacuum tubes.
            A famous tube used in radar was the magnetron.
            John's children spend six hours a day in front of the tube. (technical extension)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="3" type="" name="any inanimate object with a cylindrical, hollow form" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TUBE[+structure][+cylindrical][+hollow][-animate][+container/+clothing/+formation]
            Note: does -not- imply the transport of something (see Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There's a new tube of toothpaste in the bathroom closet.
            Pete got a job washing test tubes in the chemistry lab. (glass containers, not conduits)
            The waves at Oahu today were breaking in perfect tubes. (wave shape)
            We noticed expansive lava tubes visible in the side of the cliff.
            Lipstick tubes and nail polish were on display at the cosmetics counter.
            John got a package of tube socks for his birthday.
            They don't allow tube tops in this restaurant. 
            Bill had to replace the inner tube of his bicycle tire.
            The firm manufactures steel tube for a variety of applications.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">3</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="4" type="" name="cylindrical anatomical structures of living creatures" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TUBE[+structure][+cylindrical][+hollow][+animate][+anatomical]
            Note: implies a body part of some living organism
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She had her tubes tied after she had her second child.
            The child's Eustachian tubes were infected.
            This part of the flower is a pollen-filled tube.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">4</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense n="5" type="" name="a subway train, subway system" group="1">
        <commentary>
            TUBE[+system][+transportation][+cylindrical][+hollow][+subway]
            Note: a very specialized sense of Sense 1
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            You can ride the tube out to their home in the suburbs.
            Six bombings occurred throughout the tube this morning during rush hour.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">5</wn>
            <omega></omega><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
<sense group="1" n="6" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>

<ita count="11" ann_1_2_agreement="1.0" />
</inventory>
