<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="unit-n">
    <commentary>
        Modified definitions, added examples and senses, added commentary. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense n="1" type="" name="quantity, a standard of measure" group="1">
        <commentary>
            UNIT[+quantity][+measure][+standard]
            unit of measurement - 
            a division of quantity accepted as a standard of measurement or 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The dollar is the US unit of currency.
            A unit of wheat is a bushel.
            What is the unit cost of these laptops?
            They sent five units of blood to the OR.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">1</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="2" type="" name="a subdivision of a social organization" group="1">
        <commentary>
            UNIT[+organization][+subdivision][+military/+sport/+business]
            a subdivision or component of a larger social organization or institution
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The coach has picked his players for both the offensive and defensive units of the team.
            After the battle the soldier had trouble rejoining his infantry unit.
            They have expanded their overseas business unit by twenty percent.
            The firm is laying off 2000 workers at two of their manufacturing units.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">3</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="3" type="" name="a functional component of some larger structure or scheme" group="1">
        <commentary>
            UNIT[+structure][+component][+functional]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He was able to identify several units of nucleic acid..
            The realtor is trying to sell a three-bedroom unit in my building.
            Bob is taking three units of biology this semester.
            Her grandfather is in the intensive care unit of General Hospital.
            Can you identify all the grammatical units of this Turkish sentence?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">2 5 6</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="4" type="" name="a whole, indivisible thing" group="1">
        <commentary>
            whole, whole thing - 
            UNIT[+quantity][+whole][-divisible]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The boys are a family unit and must be adopted into the same home.
            The coach worked hard to get the players to work as a unit.
            At one time atoms were believed to be the smallest units of matter that could not be further subdivided.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.1">4</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="5" type="" name="a device with some function" group="1">
        <commentary>
            UNIT[+artifact][+device][+equipment/+furniture]
            Note: does not imply a larger whole thing, thus different from sense 3 above
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Take a look at the gearbox and the transmission unit.
            They are shipping a load of sink units by truck.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1b</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense n="6" type="" name="a police car, cruiser" group="1">
        <commentary>
            UNIT[+artifact][+car][+police]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The officer jumped into his unit and turned on the blue lights.
            Several police units were cruising up and down last night in front of that apartment building.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1i</wn>
            <omega></omega>
            <pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
<sense group="1" n="7" name="none of the above" type="">
  <commentary>
Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
  </commentary>
  <examples>
  </examples>
  <mappings>
    <wn version="2.1"></wn>
    <omega></omega><pb></pb>
    <fn></fn>
  </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
</sense>
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>

<ita count="265" ann_1_2_agreement="0.864150943396" />
</inventory>
